



# Hilary Rallo

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER & UI DESIGNER

### CONTACTS

13780 Del Corso Way Apt 217 Broomfield, CO 80020

hilaryrallo.com hrallo@icloud.com

Tel 636.368.7373

#### EDUCATION

B.A. Interactive Media Webster University 2008-2012

# KEY SKILLS

Responsive Sites
Wireframing/Mockups
Requirement Gathering
User Experience
Collaboration
QA/Testing
Implementation/Go-Live
Maintenance/Support
Troubleshooting
Agile

### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Front-end web developer that is detail-oriented, highly organized, and has the ability to pick up new tools and processes without skipping a beat. Has worked in environments with tight deadlines and shifting priorities without sacrificing quality of work. Clear communicator that bridges the gap between design and development in a way that benefits both teams and products as a whole. Works efficiently under constraints, understands aesthetic, and has the ability to extrapolate intelligently from design deliverables as well as make direct contirubtions. Solid experience in HTML5, SASS/LESS, AngularJs, jQuery, git, and ui component libraries. Continuously researches best web and usability principles to ensure bug-free and smooth user experiences. Ambition to sharpen existing skills and reach mastery level in web.

#### EXPERIENCE

# Front-end Developer

Singularity Interactive | Boulder, CO | 2/2014 - Current

Singularity Interactive is a start-up that does consulting work with aspirations to grow into an immersive gaming company. My time is spent helping to build a large-scale custom app, polymer.gloo.us.

- Prototype and build UI for custom app
- Build and upkeep a custom responsive css framework with a mobile-first approach
- Help bridge the gap between development and design teams
- Use of Git version control system to ensure code was collaborative and of the highest quality before launch
- Use of Angularis to contribute to app and consume APIs
- Use of Angular Material library to enhance the UI layer of the app

## Front-end Developer

Rose Design | St. Louis, MO | 8/2013 - 2/2014

Rose Design is a small company helping clients with custom print and web solutions.

- Helped teach other developers newer technologies such as how to use css preprocessors.
- Helped redesign and develop the internal site to give them an updated cutting edge look and feel
- · Used svn to track code
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility for all browsers
- Supported and maintained websites for retainer clients

# LESS/SASS HTML5 Javascript PHP Git

# TOOLS

Mac OS X
Adobe Suite
Sketch
Codekit
Terminal
MAMP
Chrome
Firefox
Internet Explorer
Safari
FileZilla
xcode
Sublime Text

# FRAMEWORKS

Bourbon
Bourbon Neat
Material Design
Angularjs
Bower
Grunt
Gulp
Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE (continued)

# Front-end Developer & Scrum Master Integrity | St. Louis, MO | 5/2012 - 8/2013

Integrity is a leader in the St. Louis web marketing scene, helping companies with anything from growing SEO hits to building complex web applications. While there, I was part of a web development team responsible for creating marketing sites, most often through the Wordpress.org CMS. Starting in January I was also responsible for leading a development team as the scrum master using agile.

- Lead team using Agile development process
- · Collaborated with design, project managers, and back-end development
- Converted psds into functional websites using wordpress cms with custom built themes and plugins
- Hand-coded HTML5 and CSS3 using a customized bootstrap framework built with LESS CSS
- Implemented and extended various jQuery plugins such as accordions and responsive menus
- Utilized best-practices in HTML5 structures and CSS3 styling to ensure bug-free quality code
- Collaborated with Git version control system to ensure the highest quality code before launch.
- Supported and maintained approximately 15 websites for retainer clients